2023-09-02 15:20:30 INFO - Scenario 'Font settings: Check of text theme' start 2023-09-02 15:20:30 INFO - Setting application driver using the server on 'https://hub-cloud.browserstack.com/wd/hub' 2023-09-02 15:20:55 INFO - Application on platform 'ANDROID' is ready... 2023-09-02 15:20:55 INFO - Session id - 67d216e6f235502ea8457bf5b89e8f5e0c37ed9a 2023-09-02 15:20:55 INFO - Step 0 - Close tutorial screen 2023-09-02 15:20:55 INFO - Button 'btnCloseTutorial' :: Clicking 2023-09-02 15:20:58 INFO - Step 1 - Welcome screen is opened 2023-09-02 15:20:58 INFO - Step 2 - Close welcome screen 2023-09-02 15:20:58 INFO - Button 'btnFindLibrary' :: Clicking 2023-09-02 15:20:59 INFO - Step 3 - Add library screen is opened 2023-09-02 15:21:01 INFO - Step 4 - Add library "LYRASIS Reads" on Add library screen 2023-09-02 15:21:01 INFO - Button 'Search' :: Clicking 2023-09-02 15:21:02 INFO - Text Field 'Search' :: Clearing 2023-09-02 15:21:02 INFO - Text Field 'Search' :: Typing 'LYRASIS Reads' 2023-09-02 15:21:05 INFO - Button 'LYRASIS Reads' :: Clicking 2023-09-02 15:21:06 INFO - Step 5 - Account "LYRASIS Reads" is present on Accounts screen 2023-09-02 15:21:06 INFO - Button 'tabSettings' :: Clicking 2023-09-02 15:21:10 INFO - Button 'tabSettings' :: Clicking 2023-09-02 15:21:11 INFO - Button 'Accounts' :: Clicking 2023-09-02 15:21:12 INFO - Step 6 - Enter credentials for 'LYRASIS Reads' account 2023-09-02 15:21:12 INFO - Button 'tabSettings' :: Clicking 2023-09-02 15:21:13 INFO - Button 'tabSettings' :: Clicking 2023-09-02 15:21:14 INFO - Button 'Accounts' :: Clicking 2023-09-02 15:21:15 INFO - Button 'LYRASIS Reads' :: Clicking 2023-09-02 15:21:16 INFO - Locking credential with barcode 01230000000005 2023-09-02 15:21:16 INFO - There are books on the account: 2023-09-02 15:21:17 INFO - Books without revoke in link. BookName: The Song of Achilles Distributor: framework.utilities.returningBooksUtil.Distributor@479f051b 2023-09-02 15:21:17 INFO - Books without revoke in link. BookName: The Sympathizer Distributor: framework.utilities.returningBooksUtil.Distributor@6aabe1e2 2023-09-02 15:21:17 INFO - bookName: Let's Hear It For Beagles Distributor: BiblioBoard 2023-09-02 15:21:17 INFO - bookName: Alice's Adventures in Wonderland Distributor: Palace Marketplace 2023-09-02 15:21:17 INFO - Books without revoke in link. BookName: Milk and Honey Distributor: framework.utilities.returningBooksUtil.Distributor@49531e4 2023-09-02 15:21:17 INFO - bookName: The Will to Change Distributor: Palace Marketplace 2023-09-02 15:21:17 INFO - bookName: Fahrenheit 451 Distributor: Palace Marketplace 2023-09-02 15:21:17 INFO - bookName: Goliath Distributor: Palace Marketplace 2023-09-02 15:21:17 INFO - bookName: Animal Instinct Distributor: Palace Marketplace 2023-09-02 15:21:17 INFO - Count of books on the account after opening account: 6 2023-09-02 15:21:17 INFO - Text Field 'Card' :: Clearing 2023-09-02 15:21:17 INFO - Text Field 'Card' :: Typing '01230000000005' 2023-09-02 15:21:19 INFO - Text Field 'Pin' :: Clearing 2023-09-02 15:21:19 INFO - Text Field 'Pin' :: Typing '********' 2023-09-02 15:21:21 INFO - Button 'Log in' :: Clicking 2023-09-02 15:21:28 INFO - Button 'Log ... action' :: Getting text from element 2023-09-02 15:21:28 INFO - Step 7 - Login is performed successfully 2023-09-02 15:21:49 INFO - Button 'Log ... action' :: Getting text from element 2023-09-02 15:21:50 INFO - Step 8 - Open Catalog 2023-09-02 15:21:50 INFO - Button 'tabCatalog' :: Clicking 2023-09-02 15:22:11 INFO - Step 9 - Open search modal 2023-09-02 15:22:32 INFO - Button 'Search' :: Clicking 2023-09-02 15:22:33 INFO - Step 10 - Search 'available' book of distributor 'Axis 360' and bookType 'EBOOK' from "LYRASIS Reads" and save as 'bookNameInfo' 2023-09-02 15:22:33 INFO - Count of attempts to get random book name without bad symbols-2 2023-09-02 15:22:33 INFO - randomBookName: Quicksand 2023-09-02 15:22:34 INFO - Error details button is not present 2023-09-02 15:22:34 INFO - Text Field 'Search value input' :: Sending keys 'Quicksand' 2023-09-02 15:22:36 INFO - Error details button is not present 2023-09-02 15:22:37 INFO - Step 11 - Click GET action button on EBOOK book with 'bookNameInfo' bookName on catalog books screen and save book as 'bookInfo' 2023-09-02 15:22:38 INFO - Label 'lblAuthor' :: Getting text from element 2023-09-02 15:22:38 INFO - Button 'actionButton' :: Clicking 2023-09-02 15:22:45 INFO - Step 12 - Open EBOOK book with READ action button and 'bookNameInfo' bookName on catalog books screen and save book as 'bookInfo' 2023-09-02 15:22:45 INFO - Label 'lblAuthor' :: Getting text from element 2023-09-02 15:22:46 INFO - Label 'lblBookName' :: Clicking 2023-09-02 15:22:46 INFO - Step 13 - Click READ action button on book details screen 2023-09-02 15:22:48 INFO - Button 'Read' :: Clicking 2023-09-02 15:22:48 INFO - Step 14 - Scroll page forward from 7 to 9 times 2023-09-02 15:22:48 INFO - Scrolling 7 times on reader epub screen 2023-09-02 15:23:07 INFO - Step 15 - Open font settings 2023-09-02 15:23:09 INFO - Button 'btnFontSettings' :: Clicking 2023-09-02 15:23:09 INFO - Step 16 - Change contrast to BLACK_TEXT_ON_WHITE 2023-09-02 15:23:09 INFO - Button 'setThemeLight' :: Clicking 2023-09-02 15:23:10 INFO - Step 17 - The BLACK_TEXT_ON_WHITE background is correct 2023-09-02 15:23:11 INFO - context - NATIVE_APP 2023-09-02 15:23:11 INFO - context - WEBVIEW_org.thepalaceproject.palace 2023-09-02 15:23:11 INFO - context - WEBVIEW_Terrace 2023-09-02 15:23:12 INFO - pageSourceWithSettingsStart+++++++++++++++++++++++++ 2023-09-02 15:23:12 INFO -

Week 1 of Trial: Monday

2.

Mom bought the clothes I’m wearing today. But I might as well be in a black-and-white-striped jumpsuit. I’m wearing a costume.

Then again, girls are always wearing a costume. Dressing up as the pretty, with-it girl, or the serious smart girl. Or as the totally chill I-don’t-care-how-I-look girl, with her hair in a purposely messy ponytail, a cotton bra with no underwires, and an almost-see-through T-shirt.

Mom has tried to dress me up as a perfectly normal eighteen-year-old girl who ended up here through no fault of her own. But my blouse strains across my breasts. I’ve gained weight in jail and there are little round gaps between the buttons. I look like a salesperson who has put on a doctor’s coat to dash after people in a shopping mall with my skin-care samples. Don’t think you’re fooling anyone.

“You look so nice, honey,” Mom whispered from her spot at the front. She always does that, tosses compliments after me, like trash she expects me to sort. Made-up compliments that have nothing to do with reality. I am not “beautiful” or “good at drawing.” I shouldn’t sing more or take drama classes after school. It is terribly insulting for Mom to suggest that I should, because it proves she has no idea what I’m actually good at, or when I actually do look pretty. My mom does not have sufficient interest in me to succeed in giving me a compliment that’s actually accurate.

My mom has always been inexplicably clueless. “Run out and play for a while, if you want to,” she might urge in those last few months when she didn’t have the energy to pretend she wished I would “stick around and talk about your day.” Run out and play for a while? I was old enough to vote and buy drinks at a bar. It had been legal for me to fuck for three years. What did she think I was going to do? Play hide-and-seek with the neighbors? One two three four ready or not here I come, breathless laps around the yard to check behind the same old bush, in the same old wardrobe, behind the same old broken garden umbrella in the garage. “Did you have fun?” she would ask when I came back, my clothes reeking of pot. “Would you hang your jacket in the basement, honey?”

Last night I got to talk to my mom on the phone. Her voice was higher than normal. That’s the voice she uses when someone else is listening or when she’s multitasking. Mom is almost always multitasking, straightening the house, moving things around, wiping off counters, sorting stuff. She is constantly nervous, fidgety. She always has been; it’s not my fault.

“It’s going to be fine,” she said. Several times. Her words tripped over each other. I didn’t say much. Just listened to her too-high voice. “It’s going to be fine. Don’t worry, everything will be fine.”

Sander has tried to explain what will happen during the hearing, what I can expect. In jail I got to watch an informative video in which painfully bad actors performed a trial about two guys who got into a fight at a bar. The defendant was found guilty, but not of all the charges, only like half. When we were done watching the video, Sander asked if I had any questions. “No,” I said.

What I remember best about the tax trial we visited on our class trip was that it was so quiet. Everyone spoke in a hushed voice and all other noises became exaggerated—someone clearing their throat, a door closing, a chair scraping the floor. If someone had forgotten to put their phone on silent and got a text in there, it would have roared as loud as when the lights go down at the movies and they demonstrate how they’ve just installed a new surround-sound system.

And while everything was quiet, the tax evader sat there pushing his greasy hair off his forehead. As the prosecutor read the charges out loud, the man looked at his attorney and hissed out indignant snorts. I remember thinking that he was a moron. Why was he pretending to be surprised? The prosecutor and the moron’s attorney talked one at a time, read out loud, said the same thing two or three times, and cleared their throats too much.

The whole show was lame. Not because nothing was “like it is in the movies,” but because everyone involved seemed bored to tears; the criminal himself seemed to have a hard time concentrating. Even in reality, everyone was a crappy actor who hadn’t bothered to learn his lines.

Samir, though, he didn’t think any of it was ridiculous. He leaned forward in his uncomfortable chair, rested his elbows on his knees, and scrunched up his forehead. This was his specialty: showing how earnest he was, that he took serious things seriously. Samir looked like he thought that these polyester-clad losers were the most fascinating speakers he’d ever heard in his life. And Christer was pleased. By the court and by Serious Samir. Samir seldom had to open his mouth in order to French-kiss Christer’s ass. We teased him about that afterward, me and Amanda. We liked to tease Samir. But Labbe patted him on the shoulder as if he were his youngest son and had just made the winning goal in a soccer game. “Samir gets it,” Labbe said, and Samir grinned. “Samir always gets it.”

Things were pretty good at home, too, during my second year. Mom and I still talked about stuff that had nothing to do with what time she thought my curfew should be. Mom was proud of me, or at least of the way she had raised me. She bragged about her effective methods of getting me to do exactly what it took to make her life easier. She told stories like how I slept through the night at just four months old, how I ate “everything” and held my own spoon the very first time I tried solid food. How I wanted to start school a year early, because I thought preschool was boring. How I wanted to walk to school by myself before I even turned eight, and how I “loved” being home alone without a babysitter. She said she let me start riding a balance bike before I used a real bicycle, and thanks to this, she never had to bend over and hold on to the fender to keep me from tipping over. I was able to just poof! ride a bike, and she could walk alongside in her flowy clothes and laugh just loud enough. What Mom did for me, to make my life easier, never came up, but back then, she was thoroughly convinced that I was so easy and trouble-free thanks to everything she had done right.

Today, in here, it is also quiet, I suppose. But not in the same way as during the tax trial. The air feels thick from all the important people waiting for important things to happen. The prosecutor and the lawyers are probably scared shitless that they’ll make fools of themselves. Even Sander is nervous, although you’d never notice if you didn’t know him.

They want to show what they’re made of. When Pancake talked about how he thought it would go, he used phrases like “the odds” and “our chances,” just as if he were my basketball coach and I played center on the team. He wants to win. Pancake didn’t shut up until Sander clicked his tongue.

The day’s proceedings begin when the chief judge recites some sort of roll call. He clears his throat into the microphone, and people stop whispering to each other. The judge checks to make sure everyone who is supposed to be here is here. I don’t have to raise my hand and say “present,” but the judge nods at me and reads my name. Then he nods at my attorneys and reads their names, too. He speaks slowly, but not sleepily; he’s bursting with so much solemnity that he might split the seams of his ugly suit.

The judge bids me welcome, he honestly does. I don’t say thanks for having me, because it’s not like I’m supposed to respond, but I think I’m doing all the right stuff. I look more or less as I should. I don’t smile, I don’t cry, I don’t stick my finger in any orifices. My back is straight but not too straight, and I’m trying to keep the buttons of my blouse from zinging right off.

When the chief judge tells the prosecutor that she may begin, she looks so wired that I think she’s going to stand up. But she just scoots her chair in, leans toward the little straw-shaped microphone, presses a button, and clears her throat. Like she’s taking her mark.

Out in the lawyers’ waiting room, where we were sitting before we came in here, Pancake told me that people have been standing in line to get a seat in the courtroom. “Just like a concert,” he declared, almost proudly. Sander looked like he wanted to deck him.

There’s nothing about this trial that resembles a concert. I’m no rock star. The people who are drawn to me aren’t wild groupies, they’re just scavengers. When the journalists use me as bait on their front pages, it smells like death, and the hyenas get even more worked up.

But Sander still wanted the hearing to be public. In fact, he demanded the media and the general public be allowed in, even though I’m so young. Not to make Pancake feel like a badass, but because “it is crucial to keep the prosecutor from monopolizing the news reports.” This almost certainly means that he is eager to show off his own contributions, but maybe he also imagines that my haters will be swayed if only they get to hear “my version.” Sander is wrong. That’s not going to matter. They love to hate me. They hate everything about me. Just like a concert? It seems highly unlikely that Pancake has ever been in the vicinity of live music that doesn’t belong in the dork category. If I had to guess, he listens to the classic rock station and sings along to ads for the perfect family car.

Nine months ago, one week after it all happened, there were riots in Djursholm. A bunch of guys took the metro to Mörby, transferred to bus 606, and rode all eight stops to Djursholm Square. So they could “teach those fuckers a thing or two.” Or, as the more articulate ones put it, “those fucking snobs.”

Riots usually take place in the thugs’ own run-down neighborhoods, among the public housing projects and the youth rec centers and the detoxed motorcycle guys who are “youth leaders” and “neighborhood liaisons” because no normal employer wants to touch them. And when it says in the paper that “the streets are burning,” they’re usually talking about pimped-out wrecks with tree-shaped air fresheners, not fully insured leased vehicles that are in the company’s name and are traded in as soon as one of the side mirrors stops working. But not this time.

For three days and nights, it was all-out war at Djursholm Square and around Sebastian’s house down on Strandvägen, the fanciest residential street, by the water. On the second night, there were around fifty people involved. Sander told me, he showed me the articles.

Broken windows in the frumpy shops on the square. What did they loot? A pussy-bow blouse each, plaids, and crystal wine carafes? And where did they go after they were shooed away from the Fagerman estate? Up to our house? Could they find their way? And considering how important my mom thought it was to “say a proper hello to show respect” to the very first beggar who sat outside the Coop grocery store on Vendevägen with a paper cup and a urinestained blanket, what did she do about the baseball bats and the Molotov cocktails? “Hello there. Have a nice day. Enjoy your weekend.” I wonder what Mom said to the National Task Force during the days they helped “keep order” outside our house? “Is everything okay?”

The newspapers Sander showed me speculated on Why? Whether it had to do with what Sebastian and I “symbolized,” what we were “a manifestation of,” and what we had done “had unleashed.” Did riots break out because what happened was so incredibly horrible? Were the rioters extra angry because we were rich and they weren’t? Or did violence break out solely because a group of small-time gangsters wanted a reason to fight (and because there was no soccer game to vandalize that weekend)? Whatever the reason, those thugs won’t be allowed in here.

The gallery is mostly full of journalists. Many of them are typing on laptops. No one is allowed to take pictures; there’s a “ban on photography,” and presumably they also had to give up their phones before they came in. In any case, some of the journalists are even using plain old pens and notebooks.

There’s a poor artist here, too. You’d think I was something out of Dickens, a flea-bitten kid who might get the gallows. Or some Elvira Madigan type from an old broadsheet. Why, even in this day and age, tragedy may strike. We sang that song in middle school. Naturally, Amanda cried; she was at her prettiest when she was crying but wasn’t sad for real (“adorable!”)—it would get her even more attention than usual.

Amanda is described as my best friend. In the newspapers, on TV, in the case report; even my own attorney calls her that. My best friend.

Was Amanda the person I spent the most time with, besides Sebastian? Yes. Was Amanda the person I talked to the most, besides Sebastian? Yes. Is she standing next to me in approximately 260 of my Facebook photos? Did I Snapchat with her on average two hours a day during the first four of the six months’ worth of phone records they obtained? Did she tag me in over a hundred #bff posts on Instagram? Yes. Yes. Yes.

Did I love Amanda? Was she my very best friend? I don’t know.

2023-09-02 15:23:12 INFO - pageSourceWithSettingsEnd+++++++++++++++++++++++++ 2023-09-02 15:23:13 INFO - Taking screenshot 2023-09-02 15:23:14 INFO - Test finished - logging out 2023-09-02 15:23:15 INFO - Button 'tabSettings' :: Clicking 2023-09-02 15:23:20 INFO - Button 'tabSettings' :: Clicking 2023-09-02 15:23:21 INFO - Button 'Accounts' :: Clicking 2023-09-02 15:23:22 INFO - Button 'LYRASIS Reads' :: Clicking 2023-09-02 15:23:24 INFO - Text Field 'Card' :: Getting text from element 2023-09-02 15:23:24 INFO - Text Field 'Pin' :: Getting text from element 2023-09-02 15:23:24 INFO - Button 'Log out' :: Clicking 2023-09-02 15:23:45 INFO - Button 'Log in' :: Getting text from element 2023-09-02 15:23:45 INFO - Unlocking credential for current thread 2023-09-02 15:23:45 INFO - isLoggerNullAfterAnnotation-framework.utilities.Logger@27496086

2023-09-02 14:38:23 INFO - Scenario 'Font settings: Check of font style' start 2023-09-02 14:38:23 INFO - Setting application driver using the server on 'https://hub-cloud.browserstack.com/wd/hub' 2023-09-02 14:38:51 INFO - Application on platform 'ANDROID' is ready... 2023-09-02 14:38:51 INFO - Session id - e1340c1e5025227c76d255a9fc53cc45fc49aa33 2023-09-02 14:38:51 INFO - Step 0 - Close tutorial screen 2023-09-02 14:38:52 INFO - Button 'btnCloseTutorial' :: Clicking 2023-09-02 14:38:54 INFO - Step 1 - Welcome screen is opened 2023-09-02 14:38:54 INFO - Step 2 - Close welcome screen 2023-09-02 14:38:54 INFO - Button 'btnFindLibrary' :: Clicking 2023-09-02 14:38:55 INFO - Step 3 - Add library screen is opened 2023-09-02 14:38:56 INFO - Step 4 - Add library "LYRASIS Reads" on Add library screen 2023-09-02 14:38:56 INFO - Button 'Search' :: Clicking 2023-09-02 14:38:57 INFO - Text Field 'Search' :: Clearing 2023-09-02 14:38:57 INFO - Text Field 'Search' :: Typing 'LYRASIS Reads' 2023-09-02 14:39:00 INFO - Button 'LYRASIS Reads' :: Clicking 2023-09-02 14:39:02 INFO - Step 5 - Account "LYRASIS Reads" is present on Accounts screen 2023-09-02 14:39:02 INFO - Button 'tabSettings' :: Clicking 2023-09-02 14:39:06 INFO - Button 'tabSettings' :: Clicking 2023-09-02 14:39:06 INFO - Button 'Accounts' :: Clicking 2023-09-02 14:39:08 INFO - Step 6 - Enter credentials for 'LYRASIS Reads' account 2023-09-02 14:39:08 INFO - Button 'tabSettings' :: Clicking 2023-09-02 14:39:08 INFO - Button 'tabSettings' :: Clicking 2023-09-02 14:39:09 INFO - Button 'Accounts' :: Clicking 2023-09-02 14:39:10 INFO - Button 'LYRASIS Reads' :: Clicking 2023-09-02 14:39:11 INFO - Locking credential with barcode 01230000000002 2023-09-02 14:39:11 INFO - There are books on the account: 2023-09-02 14:39:12 INFO - bookName: Snow Crash Distributor: Palace Marketplace 2023-09-02 14:39:12 INFO - bookName: Phantom Lover Distributor: Palace Marketplace 2023-09-02 14:39:12 INFO - Books without revoke in link. BookName: Unprotected Distributor: framework.utilities.returningBooksUtil.Distributor@4f9d3967 2023-09-02 14:39:12 INFO - bookName: The Black Kids Distributor: Palace Marketplace 2023-09-02 14:39:12 INFO - bookName: The Ice Queen Distributor: Palace Marketplace 2023-09-02 14:39:12 INFO - bookName: Legacy Distributor: Palace Marketplace 2023-09-02 14:39:12 INFO - bookName: The Innovators Distributor: Palace Marketplace 2023-09-02 14:39:12 INFO - Books without revoke in link. BookName: Chocolate Cream Pie Murder Distributor: framework.utilities.returningBooksUtil.Distributor@20c6cf64 2023-09-02 14:39:12 INFO - Count of books on the account after opening account: 6 2023-09-02 14:39:12 INFO - Text Field 'Card' :: Clearing 2023-09-02 14:39:12 INFO - Text Field 'Card' :: Typing '01230000000002' 2023-09-02 14:39:13 INFO - Text Field 'Pin' :: Clearing 2023-09-02 14:39:13 INFO - Text Field 'Pin' :: Typing '********' 2023-09-02 14:39:16 INFO - Button 'Log in' :: Clicking 2023-09-02 14:39:21 INFO - Button 'Log ... action' :: Getting text from element 2023-09-02 14:39:22 INFO - Step 7 - Login is performed successfully 2023-09-02 14:39:42 INFO - Button 'Log ... action' :: Getting text from element 2023-09-02 14:39:43 INFO - Step 8 - Open Catalog 2023-09-02 14:39:43 INFO - Button 'tabCatalog' :: Clicking 2023-09-02 14:40:04 INFO - Step 9 - Open search modal 2023-09-02 14:40:24 INFO - Button 'Search' :: Clicking 2023-09-02 14:40:26 INFO - Step 10 - Search 'available' book of distributor 'Palace Marketplace' and bookType 'EBOOK' from "LYRASIS Reads" and save as 'bookNameInfo' 2023-09-02 14:40:26 INFO - Count of attempts to get random book name without bad symbols-1 2023-09-02 14:40:26 INFO - randomBookName: The Crooked Castle 2023-09-02 14:40:26 INFO - Error details button is not present 2023-09-02 14:40:26 INFO - Text Field 'Search value input' :: Sending keys 'The Crooked Castle' 2023-09-02 14:40:29 INFO - Error details button is not present 2023-09-02 14:40:33 INFO - Step 11 - Click GET action button on EBOOK book with 'bookNameInfo' bookName on catalog books screen and save book as 'bookInfo' 2023-09-02 14:40:33 INFO - Label 'lblAuthor' :: Getting text from element 2023-09-02 14:40:34 INFO - Button 'actionButton' :: Clicking 2023-09-02 14:40:41 INFO - Step 12 - Open EBOOK book with READ action button and 'bookNameInfo' bookName on catalog books screen and save book as 'bookInfo' 2023-09-02 14:40:42 INFO - Label 'lblAuthor' :: Getting text from element 2023-09-02 14:40:42 INFO - Label 'lblBookName' :: Clicking 2023-09-02 14:40:42 INFO - Step 13 - Click READ action button on book details screen 2023-09-02 14:40:43 INFO - Button 'Read' :: Clicking 2023-09-02 14:40:44 INFO - Step 14 - Scroll page forward from 7 to 9 times 2023-09-02 14:40:44 INFO - Scrolling 7 times on reader epub screen 2023-09-02 14:41:06 INFO - Step 15 - Open font settings 2023-09-02 14:41:08 INFO - Button 'btnFontSettings' :: Clicking 2023-09-02 14:41:09 INFO - Step 16 - Change font style to FONT_SERIF 2023-09-02 14:41:09 INFO - Button 'setFontSerif' :: Clicking 2023-09-02 14:41:10 INFO - Step 17 - Book text displays in FONT_SERIF font 2023-09-02 14:41:10 INFO - context - NATIVE_APP 2023-09-02 14:41:10 INFO - context - WEBVIEW_org.thepalaceproject.palace 2023-09-02 14:41:10 INFO - context - WEBVIEW_Terrace 2023-09-02 14:41:12 INFO - pageSourceWithSettingsStart+++++++++++++++++++++++++ 2023-09-02 14:41:12 INFO -

1.

WHERE THERE’S A WILL, THERE’S A WISP

Felix Cassius Tiberius Carmer III spent his days learning about all the things that wanted to kill him.

There were not as many of these things as there used to be, for which he was thankful, but there were still enough to be getting on with. He learned about redcaps, who kept their namesake hats soaked with the blood of their victims. He learned about sirens, who lured sailors to their doom among jagged rocks with nothing but a song. He learned about kelpies and banshees and ghouls: where to find them (and how to escape when you did), what they looked like (or how they disguised themselves), even what they ate for breakfast (which was usually never anything good). These creatures all had one thing in common, besides their murderous impulses: they were part of the Unseelie fae. And that made them part of Carmer’s world, whether he liked it or not.

When one’s new best friend was a faerie princess—and a Seelie one at that—it was important to stay on top of one’s magical education.

It was for the sake of Carmer’s magical education, or so Grit claimed, that he was now ankle deep in stagnant, freezing water in near-total darkness, trying to distinguish the difference between half a dozen floating balls of light.

“I think a leech just bit me,” Carmer complained. He shook his leg, sending ripples sloshing through the pond. He could have sworn one of the glowing orbs tittered in amusement.

“Pay attention to the lights,” Grit scolded from somewhere up ahead. He could tell her golden faerie light apart from the others’ easily, though he couldn’t say why. It was as unique to her as a fingerprint was to humans, though it should have been indistinguishable from the others from this far away.

“I thought I wasn’t supposed to!” Carmer protested. “Or else they’ll . . . ‘enthrall’ me, or whatever it is you called it.”

“You’ve got to look at them sideways, like I told you,” explained Grit. “Catch a glimpse out of the corner of your eye. That’s all you need. Then focus.” Her light bobbed up and down.

Carmer tried to do as he was told, but like so many things in the faerie world, “looking sideways” was hardly an exact science—a fact that frustrated him to no end. He closed his eyes and took a deep breath, shivering in the December air. He opened them again, slowly this time, and looked at the reflections in the water below instead of directly out across the pond. Trying to keep his mind blank, he peered through dark lashes and the bits of hair that fell in front of his eyes. And he saw.

He saw that most of the balls of light had small figures at their centers—faeries, he knew. Only one or two were truly nothing more than swirling orbs of glowing gas and malicious intent—will-o’-the-wisps and jack-o’-lanterns who (in a less controlled scenario) wanted nothing more than to lure him into the depths of the dark water. Carmer smiled to himself; maybe he really was getting better at this sort of thing. He flicked his gaze upward, more confident now that he’d chosen the right ones, and stared into the center of one of the lights. Was there really nothing inside it at all?

He didn’t think so. He took a few steps closer, just to make sure. His knees bumped against the thin sheets of ice floating on the pond’s surface, but his legs were already so numb from the cold, he barely felt it. The orb glowed brighter, illuminating more of the pond. Carmer could even see a house on the other side of it. Was that the glow of a fire he spotted through the windows? A fire sounded lovely on a night like this. One more step, just for a closer look . . .

“CARMER.”

A streak of gold sparks shot across his field of vision, disrupting his view of both the orbs and the house. Carmer stumbled backward and nearly fell, but the muddy bottom of the pond sucked at his boots, reluctant to let such a willing prisoner go.

“That’s enough, you lot!” Grit darted in and out of the other lights. “Show’s over! Thank you for your time!”

The lights dispersed with shrugs of tiny shoulders, more than a few curious backward glances, and one or two teasing giggles. Grit stuck her tongue out at the retreating backs of the gigglers while Carmer staggered onto solid ground. The will-o’-the-wisps sank back into the pond, winking out of sight with little gurgles as they submerged themselves in the inky water. Grit kept an eye on them as she flew to Carmer’s side.

“Congratulations,” she said, hovering at his knee as he sat down. “You’ve just been enthralled.”

Carmer shook his head vigorously and ran his hands through his hair. His head felt fuzzy, much like the last time he’d fallen under the influence of faerie magic, but he was already starting to feel the true bite of the cold night air.

“I-I thought I had them,” he said, a round of shivers clacking his teeth together.

“You did,” agreed Grit. “Until they had you.”

Carmer shivered harder. “The house wasn’t real,” he guessed.

Grit shook her head; tufts of frizzy red and gold curls escaped from her messy bun. “And you should have known that.”

“Well,” said Carmer with a shrug. He tried to wring out the ends of his sodden pants, but his fingers were numb with cold. “You know what they say. P-practice m-makes p-p-perfect.”

Grit flew right in front of his face. “Hands,” she ordered.

“I—I’m fine,” Carmer stuttered through white lips.

“And I’m a giantess,” she said. “Hands. Now.”

Carmer blew on his fingers a few times before cupping his hands and extending them out to Grit, who promptly stepped inside them. Almost instantly, warmth began to radiate into his frozen fingers. Having a fire faerie for a best friend did have some benefits, after all. Carmer sighed with relief.

“That’s the best I can do for now,” Grit said, sitting cross-legged in his palms. “Let’s call it a night, shall we?”

Carmer couldn’t have agreed more.

The next morning dawned bright and clear and cold, though not nearly as chilly as the night before. As Carmer had said would happen, their days were growing warmer as they traveled south for the winter, away from Grit’s home city of Skemantis and the rest of New England. Grit stood on her favorite perch at the very topmost turret of the Moto-Manse, Carmer’s three-story motorized house on wheels, and stretched from the points of her tiny toes all the way to the tips of her fingers, yawning. As usual, she was up much earlier than Carmer—faeries didn’t need to sleep at all, strictly speaking, but with her only traveling companion in dreamland for most of the night, there wasn’t much else to keep her occupied. (Carmer, of course, couldn’t understand why she didn’t use the extra time to study his lessons on the human world, but that was because he was boring, and she was not.)

Grit lowered her arms, watching the pale sunrise, and rolled her shoulders experimentally. The muscles around her left wing had gotten stiff and sore in the night, and the cold wasn’t helping. She held on to the tip of the turret for support—the wind was quite strong that day—and slowly opened and closed both wings. The brass outline of the metal one glinted in the corner of her eye. Grit wondered if she would ever get used to that.

The Seelie faerie princess hadn’t always had two wings. She’d been born with only one, and it wasn’t until the engineering prowess of Felix Cassius Tiberius Carmer III, combined with the perfect dose of faerie magic, that she flew for the first time. Her new wing—had it really been only a few short weeks since she’d gotten it?—was a mechanical and a magical marvel. But it didn’t come without its own fair share of problems—like a tendency to literally freeze up in the cold. Grit was learning to use her magic to account for such drawbacks, but it was a process that involved a lot of trial and error (and occasionally setting things on fire).

Grit squinted into the sunrise, where a floating black spot had suddenly appeared over the horizon. It dipped dangerously close to the tree line in the distance before bobbing unsteadily back up again.

Grit scurried halfway down the Moto-Manse’s roof before she remembered to fly—that was another thing to get used to—the rest of the way to Carmer’s window. He was still asleep, his black hair tousled every which way, snoring soundly. She was loath to wake him, as she knew he didn’t always sleep as well as he could; the nightmares that plagued him from their last major encounter with Unseelie faeries made sure of that. But a skyward glance showed the black spot getting bigger—and therefore closer. It was teardrop-shaped, and not actually black at all, but striped in bright colors.

She decided to investigate. She pushed off Carmer’s windowsill with only the slightest twinge of guilt—she would turn right back if anything were amiss, she promised herself—and the moment the wind caught under her wings, she couldn’t help but break into a smile. This was the way good days started—with clear skies and the possibility of adventure sailing straight at you—not by burying your nose in books and beakers and belching engines the way Carmer did.

Truthfully, the possibility of adventure in question seemed to be having a tough time sailing straight in any direction. As she flew closer, Grit recognized the shape as a balloon. These weren’t as big as the hulking airships the humans sometimes traveled in, and they usually carried only one or two people in a hanging wicker basket.

In addition to being in obvious distress, this one also seemed to be missing a key element: the basket. A lone figure hung directly from the balloon itself, suspended in the air by nothing but a few ropes and straps.

Grit hung back, hesitating as she glided closer. She landed in a copse of trees a short way from the road and flitted from treetop to treetop, following the balloon’s progress. Surely, someone else would come driving along and see the balloonist. And there was a town just over the next rise—perhaps they could see the mysterious shape floating on the horizon. They could call for help.

But a needling voice told her it was still very early, and as untraveled as the country roads they were taking were, the likelihood of anyone else calling for help was slim. Contrary to what Carmer thought, she really did try to pay attention to the human world. Or at least, the practical bits that were worth paying attention to.

The balloon passed directly overhead, and Grit got her first look at the unfortunate passenger. He was tall, with long legs currently occupied in thrashing about in a panic; gloved hands fiddled helplessly with his harness. He looked down at the ground, which was growing nearer by the second, and then at the countryside around him—and laughed. A small, bemused laugh, to be sure, but a laugh all the same.

Only a fellow adventurer could find himself in a predicament like that and laugh. And Grit was always game to meet a fellow adventurer. She sprang up from the trees before she could second-guess the impulse and launched herself past the clueless balloonist and straight under the balloon itself.

I’m a fire faerie, Grit thought. Surely, she’d heard these things called hot air balloons for a reason.

Carmer dreamed of trains.

He dreamed of trains spewing smoke into claustrophobic underground tunnels, brakes and whistles and other things shrieking into a dark void. Black vines crept along cold concrete walls. Black iron rails twisted with magic. The very mud beneath his feet became grasping hands, ready to drag him down forever. A three-eyed man with a dripping red conductor’s cap beckoned him forward with a pointy-toothed smile.

He dreamed of running until his lungs and his legs were on fire and feeling, knowing, that he could never run fast or far enough. The train was coming for him. The Wild Hunt was coming for him, just as it had come for Gideon Sharpe.

Carmer’s eyes snapped open, the image of a blond boy being thrown into that very train still burning across his vision. He shook his head, forced himself to take deep breaths, and focused on the sound that had woken him.

It was the sound of something very large crashing into his roof.

“Grit?!” Carmer called. She had a habit of watching the sunrise from the turret in the mornings, and at five inches tall, she wasn’t exactly squish-proof.

“Urmngmf” was all he could make out of the reply.

He jumped out of his bunk and scrambled down the stairs and out the door. The sight that greeted him outside the Moto-Manse was not one he expected.

There was a balloon on his roof.

Perhaps more alarmingly, there was a man on his roof. He was fairly certain it was a man, at least, from the look of the khaki-clad limbs sprawled every which way.

“Um,” said Carmer.

“I said I’m here!” said Grit, a little more clearly this time, though he could barely hear her. A glowing light switched on somewhere under the fabric of the balloon, which had caught itself quite dramatically on the topmost turret of the Moto-Manse.

Carmer scrambled forward, unsure of what to do. The man groaned and pushed himself up onto his elbows, and then, probably realizing he wasn’t actually on the ground yet, plastered himself even more firmly to the roof. One of his boots found the peaked trim of one of the windows.

“I wouldn’t put your weight on—”

That, Carmer thought, just as the decorative molding gave way. The man’s legs swung wildly, and Carmer saw that he was attached to the balloon. The hole where the turret had pierced the fabric was getting bigger, tearing as the balloonist’s weight pulled it. A glowing light—Grit’s glowing light—tumbled a few feet down, still trapped underneath the balloon.

“Grit!” called Carmer.

“I’m fine!” came the breathless reply.

He pictured her clinging to the shingles of the roof for dear life, even as the iron in them burned her hands. Iron repelled all things fae. He hoped she’d been wearing her gloves this morning when she decided to go chasing balloons.

“Me too,” said the man hanging from Carmer’s house. “Thanks for asking!”

“Wait a minute,” said Carmer, frowning. “I’ll climb up to the attic and pull you inside.”

But Carmer’s plan never came to fruition. With a great ripping sound, the balloon tore almost all the way, dropping the balloonist down the side of the Moto-Manse until he was only a few feet off the ground. Somewhere underneath the canvas, Grit shrieked, and her light went out.

The balloonist swung around to face Carmer. He was young—perhaps only a few years older than Carmer—with smooth ebony skin and closely cropped black hair. He smiled, a blinding smile that lit up his face all the way to his eyes, hidden as they were behind thick aviator goggles (now hanging crookedly, of course). He removed the goggles with a flourish and looked down at Carmer.

“Bell Daisimer,” said the balloonist. “Professional aeronaut, at your service.”

And then the balloon tore from the roof completely, dropping him into a tangled heap at Carmer’s front door.

2023-09-02 14:41:12 INFO - pageSourceWithSettingsEnd+++++++++++++++++++++++++ 2023-09-02 14:41:13 INFO - Taking screenshot 2023-09-02 14:41:14 INFO - Test finished - logging out 2023-09-02 14:41:15 INFO - Button 'tabSettings' :: Clicking 2023-09-02 14:41:18 INFO - Button 'tabSettings' :: Clicking 2023-09-02 14:41:18 INFO - Button 'Accounts' :: Clicking 2023-09-02 14:41:19 INFO - Button 'LYRASIS Reads' :: Clicking 2023-09-02 14:41:21 INFO - Text Field 'Card' :: Getting text from element 2023-09-02 14:41:21 INFO - Text Field 'Pin' :: Getting text from element 2023-09-02 14:41:22 INFO - Button 'Log out' :: Clicking 2023-09-02 14:41:42 INFO - Button 'Log in' :: Getting text from element 2023-09-02 14:41:43 INFO - Unlocking credential for current thread 2023-09-02 14:41:43 INFO - isLoggerNullAfterAnnotation-framework.utilities.Logger@27496086